Hello and welcome to Microsoft
Azure Words of the Day
this is the show that teaches
you the Azure vocabulary!
AAD is short for Azure
Active Directory.
It is a fundamental component of
Azure and it has to do with security,
more specifically with identity
and access management.
It's sometimes called IDaaS,
or Identity as a service.
AAD has wide applications to
identify and authorize people,
inside Azure of course but also
inside your own organization.
It can also be used to manage
the identity of your users
for third party
cloud applications,
or even to manage the
identity of your customers.
There are different
editions of AAD,
Free, Basic and Premium.
Each edition has specific features, so
make sure to check the documentation here.
You can integrate with
AAD at multiple levels:
In the Microsoft cloud,
with Microsoft 365 or any of our
Platform as a Service offerings.
In Windows 10 to join a
device to an organization, etc.
It can also handle single
sign-on, B2C, B2B and more.
It's easy to use multi-factor
authentication with AAD.
For example by using the
Microsoft Authenticator app,
this is how I can use my
fingerprint to confirm
that I want to log into
a Microsoft domain,
for example the Azure Portal.
Of course this also works for a wide
range of sites and applications.
Azure Active Directory has
a lot of great features
and it makes setting up identity services
much easier than it used to be.
So make sure to check all the
links that we assembled for you here!
Thank you so much for watching
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day.
Today's word of
the day was: AAD.