Hello and welcome to
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day
this is the show that
teaches you Azure vocabulary!
Today's words of the day are: App Service
An App Service is a web server
running as a service on Azure.
So you can run web based applications,
that means HTTP based applications
for example a mobile backend,
a website, a web API etc.
The really cool thing is that
you can choose Windows
or Linux as your operating
system, so you have a choice.
And you can deploy your code,
either in a Docker container
or directly from a
Github repository,
other repositories or from a
continuous deployment solution.
Around App Services,
you can also configure a lot of features
for example different
deployment solutions,
Authorization and
Authentication,
Identity, Backups,
Custom domains,
TLS and SSL to enable
HTTPS,
you can also automatically
scale up and scale down
for example to respond to a
lot of demand very fast.
Let's check the application
now this here is an
ASP.NET Core application
running a React.JS front end,
but App Services also support
classic .NET, Java,
Node.js, Ruby, Python, PHP,
so you have a choice
for your framework.
In the Azure portal you can check
the health of your app service,
and there is also Application Insights
which is a very rich monitoring solution.
If I scroll down further we can
see more monitoring solutions,
for example the Log Stream
which allows me to see
what is happening in my
application in real time
That's quite handy to avoid
having to download the logs.
App Services have a lot of
additional functionalities,
so don't forget to
check the links here
in order to know
more about that.
Thank you so much for watching
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day
Today's words of the
day were: App Service.