Hello and welcome to Microsoft
Azure Words of the Day
this is the show that teaches
you Azure vocabulary!
Today's word of the day is: Serverless
Serverless means that your
code is running on a server,
but you don't have to worry about
that server. It is abstracted.
On Microsoft Azure, there are a few solutions
to run services in a serverless manner,
for example Azure Functions, Logic
Apps, SignalR as a service, etc etc
In an Azure Function,
you can start the execution
of your code by
observing some triggers.
There are a number of trigger
types, for example
HTTP triggers to respond
to an HTTP request;
timer trigger to execute
code on a schedule;
event grid triggers to answer to events
happening in another Azure service;
Cosmos DB trigger to execute code
when something changes in a database;
and many more.
Azure Functions also have bindings,
which allow them to input and output values
from and to different sources.
Don't forget to check the documentation
here to get more information about that!
A Logic App also starts its
execution when an event happens.
There are many
sources of events,
for example when you receive
an email in Outlook or Gmail,
when a document is modified in Office
365, and many many many more.
One really nice
feature of serverless
is that your application will
automatically scale up and down.
Here we see how an Azure
Function application is
automatically scaling
up to additional servers
when a lot of requests arrive.
This way you are covered,
if a lot of people like your product,
we will provide additional
servers to cover the demand.
And since you only pay for
what you actually consume,
serverless solutions end up
being quite cost effective.
There are more serverless
services on Azure,
so don't forget to check the links
here to know more about that.
Thank you so much for watching
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day.
Today's word
of the day was: Serverless.