Hello and welcome to Microsoft
Azure Words of the Day
this is the show that teaches
you the Azure vocabulary!
Serverless means that your
code runs on a server,
but you don't have to worry about it.
It is abstracted.
As a developer, you can concentrate on writing
the code, testing it and deploying it.
Several features are automated:
Starting the application, listening to
events to start the execution of the code,
scaling up and down
when the demand fluctuates, etc.
Typically serverless solutions are paid by
the execution time, in a consumption model.
Most cloud providers offer free tiers with
which you can run a serverless application
for a certain amount of time, or a
certain amount of executions, for free.
On Microsoft Azure,
there are quite a few solutions
that you can use to run your
code in a serverless manner,
for example Azure Functions, Logic
Apps, SignalR as a service, etc etc
Here is one example of
serverless application on Azure:
In an Azure Function, you start the execution
of your code by observing some triggers.
There are a number of trigger
types, for example
HTTP triggers to respond
to an HTTP request;
timer trigger to execute
code on a schedule;
event grid triggers to answer to events
happening in another Azure service;
Cosmos DB trigger to execute code
when something changes in a database;
and many more.
Or another example of
serverless application:
A Logic App also starts its
execution when an event happens.
There are many
sources of events,
for example when you receive
an email in Outlook or Gmail,
when a document is modified in Office
365, and many many many more.
One really nice
feature of serverless
is that your application will
automatically scale up and down.
Here we see how an Azure
Function application is
automatically scaling
up to additional servers
This way you are covered,
if a lot of people like your product,
we will provide additional
servers to cover the demand.
And since you only pay for
what you actually consume,
serverless solutions end up
being quite cost effective.
There are more serverless
solutions on Azure,
so don't forget to check the links
here in order to know more about that.
Thank you so much for watching
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day.
Today's word of the
day was: Serverless.