Hello and welcome to Microsoft
Azure Words of the Day,
the show that teaches
you the Azure vocabulary!
TLS is short for
Transport Layer Security
SSL is short for
Secure Sockets Layer.
SSL is a standard that enables secure,
encrypted transmissions over the internet.
It requires a certificate that you
can purchase from various vendors.
TLS is similar to SSL but it is a
newer, more modern version.
It also relies on certificates,
in fact when you purchase an SSL certificate,
it is often already ready for TLS.
When TLS or SSL are
setup on your web server,
this enables you to serve
web content over HTTPS.
This other abbreviation means:
Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure.
But just like HTTP
is not just for text,
HTTPS is encrypting the
whole communication.
HTTPS is often used in the web browser,
but it can also be used for APIs, etc.
In the Azure portal,
you can easily buy
or import a certificate to
secure your App Service.
Note however that web applications
on Azure are secure by default.
This is why you see
HTTPS in the location bar
when you navigate to any website
on anything.azurewebsites.net,
which is the default address for
App Services, Azure Functions, etc.
The certificate and the HTTPS settings are
needed when you want to use a custom domain,
for example TailwindTraders.com.
When navigating
to an HTTPS site,
you can see more information
about the certificate here.
This shows a valid certificate used on
a custom domain, it's safe to browse it.
You can sometimes choose
between HTTP or HTTPS.
Here we see a note in the web browser
indicating that this connection is not secure.
It is recommended to always require
HTTPS on your web application.
In Azure, you can set it
up with this switch here.
Security is a complex topic,
and we definitely need more than
just two minutes to talk about it.
So check the links here
to learn more about that.
Thank you so much for watching
Microsoft Azure Words of the Day.
Today's abbreviations of
the day were: TLS / SSL.